LAURA KAMBANIS

Phone: +44 7957993113 | Email: <u>laurakam91@gmail.com</u> | Birmingham, U.K. B93 9JX LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/laurakam/</u>| Portfolio: <u>https://laura-kam.github.io/laura-kam-react-portfolio/#portfolio</u> |

GitHub: https://github.com/Laura-Kam

Full-stack web developer with a teaching background. Focused on building practical, intuitive and user-friendly web applications which solve real-world problems, with emphasis on mobile-first design and development. Experience in JavaScript, Bootstrap, React.js, MongoDB, NoSQL, SQL, Express.js, React j.s and Node.js, as well as responsive web design. Soft-skills gained from previous employment include project management, leadership, teamwork and communication. I'm excited to use my skills as part of a quality-driven team to build better experiences for web-users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, GitHub, Express, React.js, Node.js, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap, MUI- Material Design CSS Framework, Client-Side and 3rd Party APIs.

PROJECTS

Maifrigo Zero Waste Recipe App | https://github.com/Laura-Kam/Monfrigo | https://maifrigo-recipe-app.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: App to create tasty meals using left-over food from your fridge. Ensures zero waste.
- Role: Project Manager of a Team Project.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Server-Side API, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, GraphQL, User-authentication with JWT.

Sun's Come Out Weather App | https://github.com/Laura-Kam/Sun-s-come-out-app | https://laura-kam.github.io/Sun-s-come-out-app/

- Summary: Weather app that provides current and future weather forecasts in cities.
- Role: Sole author.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Server-Side APIs.

Work Calendar App| https://github.com/Laura-Kam/Schedule-my-life | https://laura-kam.github.io/Schedule-my-life/

- Summary: App that stores events and appointments to a time slot.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, Bootstrap, Font Awesome.

Readme Generator | https://github.com/Laura-Kam/Readme-quickly. | Video: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1gMWIVDz 7tPsQE3zmaHSmv7ZrlBwwHVh/view

- Summary: A Node.js command-line application that dynamically generates a professional README.md file from user input.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS.

EXPERIENCE

Targeted Intervention Assistant University of Birmingham School.

Sept 2022-Present

Key Accomplishments:

Developed action plans for ensuring academic progress for pupils with Autism.
 Coached teachers to embed routines and behaviour for learning strategies with pupils.

History, Sociology and Spanish Teacher Secondary Teacher, Greensward Academy. Jan 2021- July 2022

Essex, UK

Key Accomplishments:

- **Project Management** Created a scheme of work for lessons spanning over seven weeks, including a booklet, assessment and all materials to ensure efficiency and consistency across the department. Trained other teachers in implementation.
- **Communication skills** Ensured that lessons were carefully scaffolded, with accessible explanations built on previous knowledge, including recall activities.
- Teamwork skills Worked collaboratively with colleagues through regular meetings scheduled to share subject knowledge and resources, delegate tasks and to assist other teachers.
- Problem Solving Checking student progress, adapting resources and managing behaviour. Taught students with low literacy in small intervention classes. Resulted in significant improvement in English language grammar and punctuation skills.
- Organisation and Time-Management: Extensive long and short-term planning well-executed to ensure daily lessons were prepared along with resources. Reports completed to the deadlines required.

Various Roles as an English Language Teacher/Assistant Oct 2013- July 2019
La Spezia, Italy/ Madrid, Spain

Key Accomplishments:

- **Project Management Skills and Teamwork -** working closely with colleagues to produce materials, share successful ideas and ensure resources are kept up to date.
- **Communication and Empathy** Working with Spanish and International Students, ensuring ideas are conveyed in accessible ways and with cultural awareness. Helping students to overcome blocks in their approach to learning.

EDUCATION

2022 Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development 2019-21 Postgraduate Certificate in Secondary History Teaching The University of Birmingham , UK Birmingham UK

2010-13 Bachelor of Arts in Modern History University of Essex, UK

Essex, UK